<div class="box docbox">
<h1>Frequently Asked Questions</h1>

<div class="docbody">

This is a partial list of questions that are often asked about Dispute Finder. 
Please <a href="mailto:robert.ennals@intel.com">email Rob Ennals</a> if 
you have a question that isn't answered here.

<ul>
<li><a href="#disputed">Isn't everything disputed?</a></li>
<li><a href="#lobby">Won't lobbyists use this to attack their opponents?</a></li>
<li><a href="#oneview">Are you trying to impose one view of the world?</a></li>
<li><a href="#mobrule">Is this mob rule?</a></li>
<li><a href="#wrong">If something is highlighted, does that mean it is wrong?</a></li>
<li><a href="#opensource">Is Dispute Finder open source?</a></li>
<li><a href="#api">Do you have an API?</a></li>
<li><a href="#who">Who created Dispute Finder?</a></li>
</ul>


<h3 id="disputed">Isn't Everything Disputed?</h3>

<p>Yes. To some extent, everything is disputed. Our aim is not to tell you 
about <em>everything</em> that is disputed by <em>anybody</em>. Our aim
is to let you know when you read something that disagrees with an opinion
expressed by a source that <em>you</em> would take seriously.</p>

<p>If a random blogger disagrees with what you are reading, then that
probably isn't very interesting, but if a newspaper you trust disagrees
then you might want to know. Similarly, you might want to know if an article
your best friend agreed with disagrees with what you are reading.</p>

<p>This is why we have the vote up/vote down buttons on each of the 
argument sources that we show you for a claim. If you like a source then vote
it up. If you don't like it then vote it down.</p>

<p>Right now, this technology doesn't function all that well, but we are working
hard to make it awesome.</p>

<h3 id="lobby">Won't lobbyists just mark their opponents sites?</h3>

<p>They probably will, and provided that they only mark things that actually are
disputed and provide good evidence in favor of their points of view, then this
is probably a good thing.</p>

<p>Remember that just because something is disputed doesn't mean
it is wrong. If you think that something someone has marked is correct then
you can help support your point of view by making sure that Dispute Finder
has good arguments in favor of your side of the story.
</p>

<p>While it is true that the side with more resources may be able to spend
more time making sure their opponents claims are marked as disputed, training
Dispute Finder to mark disputed claims doesn't take that much effort, so we 
think the scales are more fairly balanced then they are in most media.</p>

<p>If someone is abusing Dispute Finder by marking something as making
a claim that it isn't actually making then you can report their marking
as incorrect. If someone does this repeatedly then we can revoke their account
and reverse all their making.</p>

<h3 id="oneview">Are you trying to impose one view of the world</h3>

<p>Absolutely not. We are trying to do exactly the opposite.</p>

<p>When we mark something is disputed, it does <strong>not</strong> mean
that it is wrong. It just means that their are sources that you might
take seriously that argue for other points of view. It is likely that there
will also be sources that argue in favor of the claim, and we will show you
those as well.</p>

<p>The key aim of Dispute Finder is to encourage you to be aware of the 
diverse range of opinions that are out there. We want to encourage doubt
and skepticism. We hate the idea of everyone believing the same thing even
more than you do :-)</p>

<h3 id="mobrule">Is this mob rule?</h3>

<p>Not really. Dispute Finder has no idea of <em>truth</em> and does not
provide you with any metrics about how <em>true</em> a claim may on may not be. 
For example we do not take vote counts, or try to rate the reliability
of sources.</p>

<p>Our aim is to resist the mob rule that already exists by exposing you
to a diverse range of opinions that you might find interesting.</p>

<h3 id="wrong">If something is highlighted, does that mean it is wrong?</h3>

<p>No. It doesn't. If something is highlighted, it simply means it is disputed. 
Something is considered to be disputed if there is a source that we believe
you would find credible that supports a different point of view. Many disputed
claims are probably correct, and if one side of an argument is disputed then it is
likely that the other side is disputed to.</p>

<h3 id="opensource">Is Dispute Finder open source?</h3>

<p>Yes. The full <a href="http://wiki.github.com/robennals/think-link">source code</a> for Dispute Finder is available under 
an Apache License.</p>

<h3 id="api">Do you have an API?</h3>

<p>We are working on one. Please <a href="mailto:robert.ennals@intel.com">contact us</a> 
if you are interested in using our data or otherwise interfacing with Dispute Finder.</p>

<h3 id="who">Who made this?</h3>

<p>The following people have contributed to the development of Dispute Finder:</p>

<p>People at Intel Research</p>
<ul><li> <a href="http://berkeley.intel-research.net/rennals/">Rob Ennals</a> - Project lead</li>
<li> <a href="http://web.media.mit.edu/~tad/">Tad Hirsch</a> </li>
<li> Tye Rattenbury</li>
<li> <a href="http://www.agosta.org/">John Mark Agosta</a> </li>
</ul> 
People at UC Berkeley
<ul>
<li> <a href="http://www.cs.berkeley.edu/~trush/">Beth Trushkowsky</a> - 2008 Summer Intern on Think Link</li>
<li> <a href="http://www.eecs.berkeley.edu/~willettw/selectpage.html">Wes Willet</a> </li>
<li> Nick Kong</li>
<li> Nick Lanham</li>
<li> Christine Robson</li>
<li> Jesse Trutna</li>
</ul> 

</div>
</div>
